Register of the Ralph E. West papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Ralph E. West papers
1940-1982
77090
Hoover Institution Archives
20 manuscript boxes (8.0 linear feet)
Correspondence, newspaper clippings, serial issues, and other printed matter relating to the Vietnam War, the Watergate affair, and American and international politics during the presidencies of Eisenhower, Johnson, Nixon, Ford, Carter, and Reagan.
West, Ralph E.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1977.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Lieutenant colonel, United States Marine Corps.
Scope and Content of Collection
This collection contains newspaper clippings, reports, pamphlets, correspondence to prominent American politicians. The collection also includes serial issues and other printed matter relating to the Vietnam War, the Watergate affair, and American and international politics during the presidencies of Dwight Eisenhower, Lyndon B. Johnson, Richard Nixon, Gerald Ford, Jimmy Carter, and Ronald Reagan.
United States. Marine Corps.; United States--Foreign relations--1969-1974.; United States--Politics and government--1969-1974.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.; Watergate Affair, 1972-1974.
- Biographical File, 1940-1980 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  This file contains certificates, notes, a coin, and other memorabilia belonging to Ralph E. West.
- Correspondence, 1967-1982
  - Agnew, Spiro, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Albert, Carl, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Allen, Richard, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Ames, E.O., 1969 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Anderson, Martin, 1974-1982 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Andrus, Cecil, 1977 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Angleton, James, 1977 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Arcata National Corporation, 1977 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Arcata Redwood, 1977 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Baker, Howard, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Berman, Michael, 1979 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Bible, Alan, 1972 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Blumenthal, Michael, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Brennan, Jack, 1978 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Bright, John, 1969 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Brock, Bill, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 2: 1-4)
  - Brown, Jerry, 1977 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 2: 6, Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Burkley, John, 1977 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Burton, John, 1975-1982 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Bush, George, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Butz, Earl, 1974 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Byrd, Robert, 1977 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Byrne, Dick, 1977 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - California Continuing Education of the Bar, Undated (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Calkins, John, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Campbell, Truman, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - Carter, Hodding, 1979 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - Chairman of the Armed Services Committee, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Chairman of the Japanese Internment Commission, 1981 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Chancellor, John, 1976 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - Cheney, Richard, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - Chicago Tribune, 1972 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Church, Frank, 1969-1975 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - Clark, William, 1982 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Clausen, Don, 1978 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Crane, Philip, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 4: 8-9)
  - Connell, Gerald, 1970 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Costanza, Margaret, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Cowgill, Winston, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Cranston, Alan, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Crisp, Mary, 1978 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Davidson, Jim, 1977 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - Dirksen, Everett, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Dole, Bob, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Dornan, Robert, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Durbow, Elbridge, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Eastland, James, 1972 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Echohawk, John, undated (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Ehrlich, Jake, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Eizenstat, Stuart, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Elliott, Roland, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Ervin, Sam, 1973 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Eureka Newspapers Incorporated, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - The Examiner, 1980 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Feinstein, Diane, 1970-1982 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - First Monday Magazine, 1972 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Fiser, John, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Forbes, Ralph, 1975 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Ford, Gerald, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 5: 17, Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Friedersdorf, Max, 1975 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Fulbright, William, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Garn, Jake, 1979 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Gingrich, Newt, 1981 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Goldwater, Barry, 1974-1982 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Great Western Savings and Loan Association, 1977 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Griffin, Robert, 1978 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Guarino, Philip, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 7: 1-4)
  - Gurney, Edward, 1973 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Haerle, Paul, 1975 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Haig, Alexander, 1973 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - Hannaford, Peter, 1977 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - Hansen, George, undated (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Hartmann, Robert, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Hatch, Orrin, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - Hatfield, Mark, 1979 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Hauser, Rita, 1972 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - Hawkins, Jean, 1978 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - Hayakawa, S.I., 1977-1978 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Hayes, John, 1972 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - Hearst, William, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - Heinz, John, 1978 (Box-folder 8: 13)
  - Helms, Jesse, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 8: 14-15, Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Hoffman, Claire, 1978 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - Hogan, William, 1969 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - Holloway, Bruce, 1972 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - Hoover Institution, 1980 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Horton, Rogers, 1976 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - Humphrey, Gordon, 1980 (Box-folder 9: 7)
  - Irvine, Reed, undated (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - Irwin, Joan, undated (Box-folder 9: 9)
  - Jackson, Henry, 1974 (Box-folder 9: 10)
  - Johnston, Patrick, 1982 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - Jordan, Hamilton, 1977 (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - Kahle, Kent, 1976 (Box-folder 9: 13)
  - Kaluf, John, 1978 (Box-folder 9: 14)
  - Kennedy, Edward, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 9: 15)
  - Kennedy, Ted, 1972 (Box-folder 9: 16)
  - King, John, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 9: 17)
  - Kirkpatrick, Jean, 1982 (Box-folder 9: 18)
  - Laird, Melvin, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 9: 19)
  - Larie, Louis, 1969 (Box-folder 9: 20)
  - Laxalt, Paul, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 9: 21, Box-folder 10: 1-2)
  - LeDean, John, 1973 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - Leonard, Mildred, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - Levi, Edward, 1976 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - Lofton, John, 1972 (Box-folder 10: 6)
  - Lungren, John, 1974 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - MacGregor, Clark, 1972 (Box-folder 10: 8)
  - Mailliard, William, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 11: 1-2)
  - Mansfield, Mike, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - Marks, Milton, 1982 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - Marsh, John, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - McCabe, Charles, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - Meany, George, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - Meese, Edwin, 1982 (Box-folder 11: 8)
  - Milibank, Jeremiah, 1971 (Box-folder 11: 9)
  - Mitchell, Martha, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 11: 11)
  - Mills, Wilbur, 1974 (Box-folder 11: 10)
  - Molinari, John, 1972 (Box-folder 11: 12)
  - Mondale, Walter, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 11: 13)
  - Monroe, Tom, 1971 (Box-folder 11: 14)
  - Morton, Rogers, 1976 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Murphy, George, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 12: 2)
  - National Republican Congressional Committee (United States), 1972 (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - National Taxpayers Union, 1979 (Box-folder 12: 4)
  - Neighbor V, 1972 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - New York Times, 1979 (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - Nixon, Richard, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 12: 7)
  - Norris, Barbara, 1976 (Box-folder 12: 8)
  - Nozfiger, Lyn, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 12: 9)
  - O'Hara, William, 1970 (Box-folder 12: 10)
  - Packard, David, 1975 (Box-folder 12: 11)
  - Pearson, Drew, 1969 (Box-folder 12: 12)
  - Percy, Charles, 1982 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Phillips, Howard, 1980 (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - Proxmire, William, 1973-1981 (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - Publishers of Nixon's Memoir, 1978 (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 13: 5-6)
  - Reinecke, Ed, undated (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - Rhodes, John, 1977 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - Richards, Richard, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - Richardson, John, 1972 (Box-folder 13: 10)
  - Rogers, William, 1970-1977 (Box-folder 13: 11)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson, 1969 (Box-folder 13: 12)
  - Rumsfeld, Donald, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Sabin, Tom, undated (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - San Francisco Chronicle, 1973-1981 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - Schlafly, Phyllis, 1978 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - Schweiker, Richard, 1976 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - Scott, Hugh, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - Sears, John, 1976 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - Secretary of State (William P. Rogers), 1970 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - Simon, William, 1975 (Box-folder 14: 9-10)
  - Smith, Howard, 1973 (Box-folder 14: 11)
  - Somozu, Anastasio, 1978 (Box-folder 14: 12)
  - St. Clair, James, 1974 (Box-folder 14: 13)
  - Staar, Richard, 1977 (Box-folder 14: 14)
  - Stans, Maurice, 1980 (Box-folder 14: 15)
  - Stent, Ferdinand, 1973 (Box-folder 14: 16)
  - Symington, Stuart, 1973 (Box-folder 14: 17)
  - Thurmond, Strom, 1972-1981 (Box-folder 14: 18)
  - Tower, John, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - Tucker, Nion, 1974 (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - Tunney, John, 1973 (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - Udall, Morris, undated (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - United States Attorney General (John N. Mitchell), 1969-1972 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Vance, Cyrus, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - Waldie, Jerome, 1974 (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - Wall Street Journal, 1973 (Box-folder 15: 8)
  - Walt, Lewis, 1979 (Box-folder 15: 9)
  - Washington Post, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 15: 10)
  - Washington Star, 1976 (Box-folder 15: 11)
  - Weicker, Lowell, 1973 (Box-folder 15: 12)
  - White House, 1969 (Box-folder 15: 13)
  - Wilson, Bob, undated (Box-folder 15: 14)
  - Winn, David, 1979 (Box-folder 15: 15)
  - Ziegler, Ronald, 1974 (Box-folder 15: 16)
- Printed Matter, 1964-1982
  - Congressional records, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 15: 17)
  - Memoranda, 1977 (Box-folder 15: 18)
  - Monographs, 1964-1974
    - A Choice Not an Echo by Phyllis Schlafly, 1964 (Box-folder 15: 19)
    - The Betrayers by Phyllis Schlafly and Chester Ward, 1968 (Box-folder 15: 19)
    - The Eleventh Hour by Lewis W. Walt, 1971 (Box-folder 15: 19)
    - Henry Kissinger: Soviet Agent by Frank A. Capell, 1974 (Box-folder 15: 19)
    - None Dare Call it Treason by John A. Stormer, 1964 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - Lincoln's Negro Policy by Earnest Sevier Cox, 1968 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - The Myth of the Six Million by Anonymous, 1969 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - The Redwoods by Kramer Adams, undated (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - Vietnam: An Eyewitness Account by Suzanne Labin, 1964 (Box-folder 16: 2)
  - News releases, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1969-1982 (Box-folder 16: 4-5, Box-folder 17: 1-5)
  - Pamphlets, 1965-1979 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Reports, 1970-1981 (Box-folder 18: 2-4)
  - Serial issues, 1964-1981
    - Aim Report, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 18: 5)
    - The American Legion Magazine, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 18: 6)
    - Bill Mailliard Reports (Box-folder 18: 7)
    - The Call Chronicle Examiner, undated (Box-folder 18: 8)
    - Christian Anti-Communism Crusade, 1981 (Box-folder 18: 9)
    - Citizens for the Republic Newsletter, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - The Coalition Insider, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 19: 2)
    - Commanders Digest, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 19: 3)
    - The Commonwealth, 1978 (Box-folder 19: 4)
    - Current Foreign Policy, undated (Box-folder 19: 5)
    - Dan Smoot Report, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 19: 6)
    - Department of the Treasury News, 1978 (Box-folder 19: 7)
    - Dollars and Sense, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 19: 8)
    - First Monday, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 19: 9)
    - Gist, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 19: 10)
    - Heritage Today, 1980 (Box-folder 19: 11)
    - Human Events, undated (Box-folder 19: 12)
    - John Heinz Reports, undated (Box-folder 19: 13)
    - Latin American Report, undated (Box-folder 19: 14)
    - Mediplus, 1981 (Box-folder 19: 15)
    - Member's Report, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 19: 16)
    - The Plain Truth, 1981 (Box-folder 19: 17)
    - Public Information Series, undated (Box-folder 19: 18)
    - Reagan Country Update, undated (Box-folder 19: 19)
    - The Retired Officer, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 20: 1)
    - The Secretary of State, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 20: 2)
    - Senior Citizen News, 1979 (Box-folder 20: 3)
    - Time Magazine, 1975 (Box-folder 20: 4)
    - Washington Report, 1973-1981 (Box-folder 20: 5)
- Speeches and Writings, 1941-1980, undated
  - "The 1917 Brand of Preparedness,", undated (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - "Americanism,", undated (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - "A Few Reflections on America in the Midst of a Belligerent World,", undated (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - "The Attempted Modernization of China,", undated (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - "Don't Believe Everything You Read,", undated (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - "North Oakland Kiwanis,", undated (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - "Peanuts Gunther,", undated (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - "Rearmament for Peace,", undated (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - "Redwood Park Suggestions,", undated (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - "Summary of Impressions in the Communist World of Eastern Europe,", undated (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - "How Close Are We to War?", circa 1941 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - "Neutrality,", circa 1941 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - "The Eastern Europe Communist World,", 1964 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - "Thirty Three Days Behind the Iron Curtain,", 1964 (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - "Press Club Breakfast Speech,", 1977 (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - "Re: the Redwood National Park Controversy,", 1977 (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - "Operation PUSH: People United to Save Humanity,", 1978 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - "President Carter's Iran Crisis: America Held Hostage,", 1980 (Box-folder 20: 7)